这是眉山市二零二五年初中学业水平及高中阶段学校招生考试英语听力部分。该部分分为第。一、第二两节。注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到客观题答题卡上现在是听力。试音时间。
They were really interesting to watch.
How fantastic the Dragon Boat teams were!
Yes, that's true.
And I really liked eating
粽子.
Oh, me too.
The sweet ones are my favorite.
Do you know why people eat on this festival?
粽子
In order to honor Qu
屈原,
a famous poet in Chinese
是因到此结束。听力考试正式开始。第一节，听下面五段短对话。每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
B, Monkeys, they are clever and funny.
三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你将有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话读两遍。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Lucy, which animal do you like best?
Monkeys, elephants or giraffes?
Monkeys, they are clever and funny.
Mark, I called you up this morning but you didn't answer.
What were you doing?
Sorry Amy, I was playing the guitar in my room.
Mark, I called you up this morning but you didn't answer.
What were you doing?
Sorry Amy, I was playing the in my room.
Oh, the t looks nice on me.
I'll take it.
How much is it?
It's eighteen dollars, madam.
Oh, the t -shirt looks nice on me.
I'll take it.
How much is it?
It's eighteen dollars,
Hi Cathy, are you going to watch the performance tomorrow?
Yes, and I'm going there with my mom.
The wind is blowing hard outside.
You'd better stay at home, and you can do some reading,
You'd better stay at and you can do some reading, Sally.
The is blowing hard
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面五段长对话或独白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前。你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。听第六段对话，回答第六、第七两个小题。现。
The wind is blowing You'd better stay at outside.
some What's the date today, Lisa?
It's March the 17th.
Oh, tomorrow is mom's birthday.
Do you have any ideas?
I'm going to make a cake for her.
What about you, Mike?
I have no idea.
Dad said he would buy her a new watch.
Why don't you buy her some flowers?
Sounds like a good idea.
I'll buy her some roses.
She likes them best.
I believe she will be very happy.
What's the date today, Lisa?
It's March the 17th.
Oh, tomorrow is mom's birthday.
Do you have any ideas?
I'm going to make a cake for her.
What about you, Mike?
I have no idea.
Dad said he would buy her a new watch.
Why don't you buy her some flowers?
Sounds like a good idea.
I'll buy her some roses.
She likes them best.
I believe she will be very happy.
听第七段对话，回答第八至第十三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
What's date 17th.
Morning. What's the matter?
I have a stomach ache.
Please lie down and let me check.
What did you eat yesterday?
I had some barbecue and ice cream.
At midnight, my stomach started to hurt and I couldn't sleep well the whole night.
Well, I'll give you some medicine.
You need to take it three times a day for two days.
Okay. Anything else?
You'd better have a good rest.
And if you don't feel better, please come back to the hospital in time.
Thank you. Morning.
What's the matter?
I have a stomach ache.
Please lie down and let me check.
What did you eat yesterday?
I had some barbecue and ice cream.
At midnight, my stomach started to hurt and I couldn't sleep well the whole night.
Well, I'll give you some medicine.
You need to take it three times a day for two days.
Okay. Anything else?
You'd better have a good rest.
And if you don't feel better, please come back to the hospital in time.
Thank you. Good evening.
听第八段对话，回答第十一至第十三三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
What can I do for you?
Could you please show me a table by the window?
Sorry. There is no table by the window now.
How about a table in the center?
Okay. This way, please.
What would you like?
I'd like chicken, beef,
carrots, and two glasses of apple juice.
Okay. It's six o now.
Your order will be ready in twenty minutes.
Oh, my friend hasn't arrived yet.
Please get it ready in thirty minutes.
No problem. Good evening.
What can I do for you?
Could you please show me a table by the window?
Sorry. There is no table by the window now.
How about a table in the center?
Okay. This way, please.
What would you like?
I'd like chicken, beef,
carrots, and two glasses of apple juice.
Okay. It's six o now.
Your order will be ready in twenty minutes.
Oh, my friend hasn't arrived yet.
Please get it ready in thirty minutes.
No problem. Thank you.
听第九段对话，回答第十四至第十六三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读。读这三个小题。
Hey, Kevin. What are you doing?
I'm planning a trip to Sichuan.
Oh, I went there last summer.
Really? Tell me something about it, Alice.
Sichuan has lots of and mountains, such as the Mingjiang River, Mount Emei, and
Mount Qingcheng. And it has other special attractions, too.
Chengdu Panda Research Base is a must to visit.
You can see many cute pandas there.
Wonderful. I'm a panda fan.
I can't wait to go.
And I also went to the Sanxingdui Museum.
It's an unforgettable experience.
Wow. I like history.
And visiting museums is my favorite.
By the way, Sichuan is well known for its local food, like hot pot, mapo tofu,
and donpo pork.
Sounds delicious. Thanks for your sharing.
It's really helpful.
Hey, Kevin. What are you doing?
I'm planning a trip to Sichuan.
Oh, I went there last summer.
Really? Tell me something about it, Alice.
Sichuan has lots of rivers and mountains, such as Mingjiang River, Mount Emei, and
Mount Qingcheng. And it has other special attractions, too.
Chengdu Panda Research Base is a must to visit.
You can see many cute pandas there.
Wonderful. I'm a panda fan.
I can't wait to go.
And I also went to the Sanxingdui Museum.
It's an unforgettable experience.
Wow. I like history.
And visiting museums is my favorite.
By the way, Sichuan is well known for its local food, like hot pot, mapo tofu,
and donpo pork.
Sounds delicious. Thanks for your sharing.
It's really helpful.
听下面一段独白，回答第十七至第二十四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小。一。
Hi, I'm John May from No.
Middle School. Today, I'd like to share something I love about our school with you.
In our school, we have an area called Happy Farm.
On that farm, each class has a small piece of land, and we can grow fruit and
vegetables there. Every morning, we spend some time looking after all the plants.
I enjoy doing planting activities because it's relaxing and also a good way to learn
about nature. My class has an orange tree, and we take good care of it.
Next month, we will be able to pick our own oranges.
And then, each of us can bring some fresh oranges back home.
It's amazing to share the oranges grown by ourselves with our family.
I think they are the most delicious in the world.
Hi, I'm John May from No.
Middle School. Today, I'd like to share something I love about our school with you.
In our school, we have an area called Happy Farm.
On that farm, each class has a small piece of land, and we can grow fruit and
vegetables there. Every morning, we spend some time looking after all the plants.
I enjoy doing planting activities because it's relaxing and also a good way to learn
about nature. My class has an orange tree, and we take good care of it.
Next month, we will be able to pick our own oranges.
And then, each of us can bring some fresh oranges back home.
It's amazing to share the oranges grown by ourselves with our family.
I think they are the most delicious in the world.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将你的答案转涂到客观题答题卡上。
Thank you watching!
Thank you for watching!
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you!
听力部分到此结束。